Guide to the Institute for Research on Educational Finance and Governance (U.S.) Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Institute for Research on Educational Finance and Governance (U.S.) Records
1979-1990
SC0587
Institute for Research on Educational Finance and Governance (U.S.)
19.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 2000.
Information about Access
This collection is held in off-site storage and there will be a considerable delay in paging materials.
Historical Note
The Institute for Research on Educational Finance and Governance (IFG) was established in 1979 with a five-year committment from the National Institute of Education; it was administered through the School of Education at Stanford University. Its research program focused on educational finance and economics, educational politics, educational organizations, and law and education.
Scope and Content
These records consist of files on reports and papers published by IFG which include the text of the paper or report, with some correspondence, memoranda, press releases, and other materials. Authors represented by a number of publications include Michael W. Kirst, Henry M. Levin, Russell W. Rumberger, and Hans N. Weiler.
The published version of most of these papers is available in the Stanford University Libraries; researchers should consult those first. This collection is held in off-site storage and there will be a considerable delay in paging materials.
Access Terms
Kirst, Michael W.; Levin, Henry M.; Rumberger, Russell W.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education.; Weiler, Hans N.; Education--Finance--Research.; Education--Research.; School management and organization--Research.
Collection Contents
- 79-A1. Levin. Assessing the Equalization Potential of Education (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 79-A2. Cohen and Miller. Increased Accountability and the Organization of Schools (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 79-A3. Hollister. School Bureaucratization as a Result of Parents' Demands (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 79-A4. Burbules, Sherman and Lord. Equity, Equal Opportunity and Education (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 79-A5. Tyack, Kirst and Hansot. Educational Reform: Retrospect and Prospect (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 79-A6. Wilkes, Eaton, Wood and Dornbusch. Centralization and Tighter Coupling in Education Through Program Evaluation (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 79-A7. Cronbach and Schaeffer. Setting Cut Score in Selection: A Mathematical Structure for Examining Policies (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 79-A8. Salomon, King and Yuen with commentary by Talbert. School Governance and Sociological Correlates (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 79-A9. Meyer, Scott and Deal. Institutional and Technical Sources of Organizational Structure (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 79-A10. Sirowy and Inkeles. Cross-National Comparison of Student to-Teacher Ratios (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 79-A11. Sirowy and Inkeles. Educational System Development and Convergence: A Literature Review (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 79-A12. Weiler. Notes on the Comparative Study of Educational Innovation (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 79-A13. Bridges. Job Satisfaction and Teacher Absenteeism (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 79-A14. Chambers. The Hedonic Wage Technique as a Tool for Estimating the Costs of School Personnel (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 79-A15. Field. Microeconomics, Socialization and Norms (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 79-B1/F and E. Levin. Educational Performance Standards: Image or Substance (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 79-B2/F and E. Levin. The Dilemma of Comprehensive Secondary School Reforms in Western Europe (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 79-B3. Kirst. New Politics of State Education Finance (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 79-B4. Chambers. Educational Cost Differentials and the Allocation of State Aid for Elementary/Secondary Education (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 79-B5. Catterall and Thresher. Proposition 13: The Campaign, The Vote and the Immediate Aftereffects for California Schools (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 79-B6. Jackson. Community Colleges and Budget Reductions (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 79-B7/F and E. Strobber and Best. Female/Male Salary Differential in Public Schools (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 79-B8/P and L. Weiler. Education and Development: From the Age of Innocence to the Age of Skepticism (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 79-B9/P and L. Weiler. Towards A Political Economy of Educational Planning (Box 1, Folder 24)
- 79-B10/P and L. Wrubel. An Assessment of the Impact of the Courts on Local School Boards (Box 1, Folder 25)
- 79-B11. Chambers. The Development of a Cost of Education Index: Some Empirical Estimates (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 79-B12. Levin. Educational Vouchers and Social Policy (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 79-B13. Levin. Educational Earnings of Black and the Brown Decision (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 79-B14. Levin. Individual Entitlements for Recurrent Education (Box 1, Folder 29)
- 79-B15. Hartman. Estimating the Cost of Educating Handicapped Children (Box 1, Folder 30)
- 79-B16. Levin. Economic Democracy, Education and Social Change (Box 1, Folder 31)
- 79-B17. Burbules, Nicholas and Sherman. Equal Educational Opportunity: Ideal or Ideology (Box 1, Folder 32)
- 79-B18. Katz. Proposition 13: The First Year (Box 1, Folder 33)
- 79-B19. Levin. The Identity Crisis of Educational Planning (Box 1, Folder 34)
- 79-B20. Meyer. The Impact of the Centralization of Educational Funding and Control (Box 1, Folder 35)
- 79-B21. Rumberger. The Changing Skill Requirements of Jobs in the U.S. Economy (Box 1, Folder 36)
- 79-B22. Kirp. Barnyard Cacaphony? Judging and Politicking in School Desegregation (Box 1, Folder 37)
- 80-A1. Weiler. The Fallacies and Prospects of Educational Planning (Box 1, Folder 38)
- 80-A2. Pacheco. Educational Vouchers and their Implications for Equity (Box 1, Folder 39)
- 80-A3. Calfee and Pessirilo-Jurisic. Perceived Changes in California Schools and Classrooms (Box 1, Folder 40)
- 80-A4. Michaelson. A Theory of Decision-Making in the Public Schools (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 80-A5. Jackson. Efficiency and Enrollment Modification in Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 80-A6. March. Footnotes to Organizational Change (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 80-A7. Duke, Showers and Imber. Teachers as School Decision Makers (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 80-A8. Cronbach. Selection Theory for a Political World (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 80-A9. Talbert. School Organization and Institutional Change: Exchange and Power in Loosely Coupled Systems (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 80-A10. Wilcox. The Ethnography of Schooling: Implications for Educational Policy- Making (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 80-A11. Geiogue. Effects of Tax Limitation Measures on Recurrent Education Activities in California (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 80-A12. Kurland. Recurrent Education Activities and Finance in New York State (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 80-A13. Smith. Employer-Sponsored Recurrent Education in the United States (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 80-A14. Wagner. An Invention of Post-Compulsory Education and Training Programs in The United States and Sources of Support (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 80-A15. Kirst and Somers. Collective Action Among California Educational Interest Groups: A Logical Response (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 80-A16. Coombs. Opportunities in the Comparison of State Education Policy Systems (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 80-A17. Murnane. Seniority Rules and Educational Productivity: Understanding the Consequences of a Mandate for Equality (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 80-A18. Akin and Wykoff. Some Effects of Tax Substitution on the Finance of Public Education (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 80-A19. Windham. Benefits and Financing of American Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 80-A20. Schaeffer and Cronbach. Tables Relating Quality of Persons Hired to Selection Rate for Minority Applicants (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 80-B1. Hartman. Policy Effects of Special Education Funding (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 80-B2. Levin. Teacher Certification and the Economics of Information (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 80-B3. Inkeles. Convergence and Divergence in Industrial Societies (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 80-B4. Carnoy. Educational Innovation in Latin America (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 80-B5. Osman. School Referenda: Local Sovereignty vs. Equality in Resource Allocation (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 80-B6. The Impact of Bargaining and Bargaining Statues on the Earnings of Public School Teachers (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 80-B7. Levin and Woo. An Evaluation of the Costs of Computer-Assisted Instruction (Box 2, Folder 24)
- 80-B8. Kirst and Opperman. State Services for Children: An Exploration of Who Benefits (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 80-B9. A Plain Man's Guide to the Finance of British Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 80-B10. Blaug. Economic Methodology in a Few Easy Lessons (Box 2, Folder 27)
- 80-B11. Valente. The Role and Influence of State Courts on Educational Policy (Box 2, Folder 28)
- 80-B12. Murphy. The State Role in Education (Box 2, Folder 29)
- 80-B13. Carnoy. Marxian Approaches to Education (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 80-B14. Lehne and Rosenthal. Research Perspectives on State Legislatures and Educational Policy (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 80-B15. Ramirez and Meyer. Comparative Education: The Social Construction of the Modern World (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 80-B16. Glenny and Scmidtlein. The Role of The State in the Governance of Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 80-B17. Shapiro. Federal Regulation of Education (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 80-B18. Kirst and Jung. The Utility of a Longitudinal Approach in Assessing Implementation (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 80-B19. Lenhardt. On Legal Authority, Crisis of Legitimacy and Schooling in the Writings of Max Weber (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 80-B20. Benson. Centralization and Legalization in Vocational Education: Limits and Possibilities (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 80-B21. Waiser. An Alternative Theoretical Approach for the Study of Literacy and its Role in Development (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 80-C1. Kirst and Garms. The Demographic, Fiscal, and Political Environment of Public School Finance in the 1980s (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 80-C2. Kirst. A Tale of Two Networks: The School Finance Reform Versus the Spending and Tax Limitation Lobby (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 80-C3. Cronin. Big City School Bankruptcy (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 80-C4. Levin. Youth Unemployment and its Educational Consequences (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 81-A1. Stern. Assessing Economic Feasibility of on-the-job Training (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 81-A2. Cronbach and Schaeffer. Extensions of Personnel Selection Theory to Aspects of Minority Hiring (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 81-A3. Chambers. Cost and Price Level Adjustments to State Aid for Education (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 81-A4. Chambers and Hartman. A Cost-Based Approach to the Funding of Educational Programs; An Application to Special Ed (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 81-A5. Bryant. Directory of Researchers in Educational Finance and Governance (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 81-A6. Thresher. Annotated Bibliography of Tax and Expenditure Limitation Literature (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 81-A7. Keith. Politics of Textbook Selection (Box 3, Folder 20)
- 81-A8. Hartman and Haber. School Finance Reform and Special Education (Box 3, Folder 21)
- 81-A9. Osman and Gemello. Revenue/Expenditure Limits and Override Elections: The Experience of California (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 81-A10. Mitchell. State Legislatures and the Social Sciences (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 81-A11. Levin. Education and Organizational Democracy (Box 3, Folder 24)
- 81-A12. Chubb. The Political Economy of "Excessive" Regulation: The Case of Educational Opportunity (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 81-A13. Fass. The New Deal: Anticipating a Federal Education Policy (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 81-A14. Kagan. Regulating Business, Regulating Schools: The Problem of Regulatory Unreasonableness (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 81-A15. Millot. Student Services: Rationale, Cost and Utilization (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 81-A16. Weiler. Equal Protection, Legitimacy and the Legalization of Education: The Role of the Federal Constitutional Court in West Germany (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 81-A17. Weiler. Compensatory Legitimization in Educational Policy (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 81-A18. Benveniste. Implementation and Intervention Strategies: The case of PL 94-142 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 81-A19. Talbert. Institutional Change and School Organization: A Trend Towards Standardized Instructional Policy (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 81-A20. Berman. From Compliance to Learning: Implementing Legally Induced Reform (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 81-A21. Stern and Timar. Conflict and Choice in Public Education (Box 4, Folder 10)
- 81-A22. Hoachlander. Distributing Federal Categorical Aid by Formula: The Case of Vocational Education (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 81-B1. Freeman and Hannan. Effects of Resources and Enrollments on Growth and Decline in School Districts (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 81-B2. Chubb. Regulating Economic Opportunity (Box 4, Folder 13)
- 81-B3. Chambers. The Development of A Cost-of-Education Index for the State of California (Box 4, Folder 14)
- 81-B4. Rumbereger. Why Do Kids Drop Out of High School? (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 81-B5. Cooke and Rousseau. The Problems of Complex Systems: A Model of Systems Problem Solving Applied to Schools (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 81-B6. Wolfe. School Outcomes of Chronically Ill Children and their Siblings: A Multivariate Approach (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 81-B7. Hanushek. Sources of Black-White Earning Differences (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 81-B8. Hartman. Projecting Special Education Costs (Box 4, Folder 19)
- 81-B9. Jackson. Sociologic, Economic and Policy Influence on College Going Decisions (Box 4, Folder 20)
- 81-B10. Meyer. Organizational Factors Affecting Legalization in Education (Box 4, Folder 21)
- 81-B11. Olivas. Research on Hispanic Education: Students Finance and Governance (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 81-B12. Jensen. Desegregation in Boston: The Federal Court as School Administration (Box 4, Folder 23)
- 81-B13. Levin, Seidman and CCEE. Towards a Meta Cost Effectiveness Analysis of Education (Box 4, Folder 24)
- 81-B14. Olivas. Financial Aid: Accessing And Packaging Policies of Disadvantaged Students (Box 4, Folder 25)
- 81-C1. Kirst. The State Role in Education Policy Innovation (Box 4, Folder 26)
- 81-C2. Hansot and Tyack. The Dream Deferred: A Golden Age for Women School Administrators (Box 4, Folder 27)
- 82-A1. Benveniste. Covert Purposes in Federal-State-Local Linkages: The Case of Bilingual Education (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 82-A2. Griffin and Jensen. The Legalization of State Educational Policy Making in California (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 82-A3. Tweedie. The Politics of Legalization in Special Education Reform (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 82-A4. Levin. The Making (and Unmaking) of a Civil Rights Regulation: Language, Minorities, Children and Bilingual Education (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 82-A5. Bardach. Educational Paperwork (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 82-A6. Rhode. Conflicts of Interest in Education Reform Litigation (Box 5, Folder 6)
- 82-A7. Tyack. Toward a Social History of Law and Education (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 82-A8. Index of the IFG Publications for the Years 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 82-A9. Richards. Employment Reform or Pupil Control? Desegregation, Bilingualism and Hispanics (Box 5, Folder 9)
- 82-A10. Banks. Organizational Report in a School District: State and Federal Programs (Box 5, Folder 10)
- 82-A11. Clune. The Deregulation Critique of the Federal Role in Education (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 82-A12. Bradbury, et al. Proposition 2-1/2: Initial Impacts (Box 5, Folder 12)
- 82-A13. Swidler. The Culture of Policy Aggregate vs. Individual Thinking (Box 5, Folder 13)
- 82-A14. Tsang and Levin. The Impact of Intergovernmental Grants on Educational Spending (Box 5, Folder 14)
- 82-A15. Peterson and Love. Territorial Interests and Educational Policy (Box 5, Folder 15)
- 82-A16. Scott/Meyers. The Organization of Institutional Sectors (Box 5, Folder 16)
- 82-A17. Kogan and Atkin. Legitimating Education Policy: The Use of Special Committees (Box 5, Folder 17)
- 82-A18. Levin and Tsang. Federal Grants and National Educational Policy (Box 5, Folder 18)
- 82-A19. Chambers and Parrish. The Issue of Adequacy in the Financing of Public Education (Box 5, Folder 19)
- 82-20. Hartman and Hartman. Local Special Education Planning: Model User's Manual (Box 5, Folder 20)
- 82-A21. Upshaw. Directory of Researchers in Education Finance and Governance (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 82-A22. Weiler. The Politics of Educational Reform: Notes on the Comparative Study of Innovation in Education. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 82-A23. Rumberger and Daymont. The Economic Value of Academic and Vocational Training Acquired in High School (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 82-A24. Stackhouse. The Effects of State Centralization in Administration and Macrotechnical Structure in Contemporary Secondary Schools (Box 6, Folder 4)
- 82-A25. Friedman. Limited Monarchy. The Rise and Fall of Student Rights (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 82-A26. Richards and Encarnation. Race and Educational Employment (Box 6, Folder 6)
- 82-A27. Neal and Kirp. The Allure of Legalization Reconsidered: The Case of Special Education (Box 6, Folder 7)
- 82-B1. Kirst. Teaching Policy and Federal Categorical Programs (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 82-B2. Catterall and Levin. Public and Private Schools: Evidence on TTCs (Box 6, Folder 9)
- 82-B3. Chaffee. Rational Budgeting? The Stanford Case (Box 6, Folder 10)
- 82-B4. Weiler. Education, Public Confidence and the Legitimacy of the Modern State (Box 6, Folder 11)
- 82-B5. Encarnation. Why Create a Separate Department of Education? (Box 6, Folder 12)
- 82-B6. Presley. Selection and Stratification in Graduate Education (Box 6, Folder 13)
- 82-B7. Rumberger. The Structure of Work and the Underutilization of College-Educated Workers (Box 6, Folder 14)
- 82-B8. Levin. Education and Work (Box 6, Folder 15)
- 82-B9. Levin. School Finance (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 82-B10. Chambers and O'Brien. Cost Consequences in the Demographics of Education (Box 6, Folder 17)
- 82-C1. Kirst. Policy Implications of Individual Differences and the Common Curriculum (Box 6, Folder 18)
- 83-A1. Kirst and Meister. The Role of Issue Networks in State Agenda Setting (Box 6, Folder 19)
- 83-A2. Rumberger. Social Mobility and Public Sector Employment (Box 6, Folder 20)
- 83-A3. Rumberger. The Job Market For College Graduates 1960-1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- 83-A4. Levin and Rumberger. The Educational Implications of High Technology (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 83-A5. Kirp and Jensen. What Does Due Process Do? Parc v. Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Reconsidered (Box 7, Folder 2)
- 83-A6. Baro. Federalism, Equity and the Distribution of Federal Grants (Box 7, Folder 3)
- 83-A7. Index of IFG Publications for the Year 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- 83-A8. Rumberger. A Conceptual Framework For Analyzing Work Skills (Box 7, Folder 5)
- 83-A9. Grubb. Occupational Demand and the Rise of Post Secondary Vocational Education (Box 7, Folder 6)
- 83-A10. Muir. Teachers' Regulation of the Classroom (Box 7, Folder 7)
- 83-A11. Rumberger. The Employment Impact of Government Spending (Box 7, Folder 8)
- 83-A12. Fine. Just Schools (Box 7, Folder 9)
- 83-A13. Elmore. Education and Federal Doctrinal, Func. and Strategic Views (Box 7, Folder 10)
- 83-A14. Rumberger. Education, Unemployment and Productivity (Box 7, Folder 11)
- 83-A15. Carnoy. The Role of Capital in Improving Productivity and Creating Jobs (Box 7, Folder 12)
- 83-A16. Richards. Bilingualism and Hispanic Employment: School Reform or Social Control? (Box 7, Folder 13)
- 83-A17. Daymont. Worker Productivity Employment and Aging (Box 7, Folder 14)
- 83-A18. Combs. The Federal Judiciary and Northern School Desegregation (Box 7, Folder 15)
- 83-A19. Levin. About Time for Educational Reform (Box 7, Folder 16)
- 83-A20. Bridges. The Management of Teacher Incompetence (Box 7, Folder 17)
- 83-A21. Brackett, Chambers and Parish. The Legacy of Rational Budgeting Models in Education and a Proposal for the Future (Box 7, Folder 18)
- 83-A22. Hannan and Freeman. School District demography and Governance. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- 83-A23. Bridges and Groves. The Id. Remediation and Dismissal of Incompetent Teachers. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- 83-B1. Willms. Public and Private Schools: The Evaluation of Choice in Education (Box 7, Folder 21)
- 83-B2. Mitchell and Encarnation. Alternative State Policy Mechanisms for Influencing School Performance (Box 8, Folder 1)
- 83-B4. O'Brien. A Model to Predict Future Composition of a Schools District's Teaching Force (Box 8, Folder 2)
- 83-B5. Kirp and Jung. Schools and Rules: Understanding Legalization in Comparative Perspective (Box 8, Folder 3)
- 83-C1. Kirp. The Fourth R: Reading, Writing, 'Rithmetic and Rules (Box 8, Folder 4)
- 83-C2. Levin and Schutze. Economic and Political Dimensions of Recurrent Education (Box 8, Folder 5)
- 83-C3. Schutze. Educational Leave in Europe (Box 8, Folder 6)
- 83-C4. Kirst. A New School Finance for a New Era of Fiscal Constraint (Box 8, Folder 7)
- 83-C5. Levin. Can The Social Sciences Solve the Problem of Unemployment? (Box 8, Folder 8)
- 83-C6. Kirst. The Turbulent Nature of U.S. Secondary School Curriculum (Box 8, Folder 9)
- 83-C7. Kirst. State Education Policy in an Era of Transition (Box 8, Folder 10)
- 83-C8. Kirp and Jensen. The New Federalism Goes to Court (Box 8, Folder 11)
- 84-A1. Bridges and Gumport. The Dismissal of Tenured Teachers for Incompetence (Box 8, Folder 12)
- 84-A2. Index of Publication for the Years 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- 84-A3. Gilliland and Radle. Characteristics of Public and Private Schools in the San Francisco Bay Area (Box 8, Folder 14)
- 84-A4. Rumberger and Levin. Forecasting The Impact of New Technologies on the Future Job Market (Box 8, Folder 15)
- 84-A5. Scott. Organizational Aspects of Conflicting Regulations (Box 8, Folder 16)
- 84-A6. Chubb. The Political Economy of Federal Aid to Education (Box 8, Folder 17)
- 84-A7. Encarnation and Richard. Social Policy And Minority Employment in Public, Catholic and Private Schools (Box 8, Folder 18)
- 84-A8. Peters. Directory of Researchers (Box 8, Folder 19)
- 84-A9. Kutner. The Effect of Pension Wealth on the Age of Retirement (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 84-A10. Talbert. Toward an Institutional-Contingency View of School Organization (Box 9, Folder 2)
- 84-A11. Cost Effectiveness of Four Educational Interventions (Box 9, Folder 3)
- 84-A12. Rumberger. High Technology and Job Loss (Box 9, Folder 4)
- 84-A13. Meister. Successful Integration of Microcomputers in an Elementary School (Box 9, Folder 5)
- 84-A14. Bridges and Groves. Managing the Incompetent Teacher (Box 9, Folder 6)
- 84-A15. Encarnation and Richards. Race and Educational Employment: Public and Catholic Schools Compared (Box 9, Folder 7)
- 84-A16. Scott and Meyer. Environmental Link and Organizational Complexity: Public and Private Schools (Box 9, Folder 8)
- 84-A17. Ballayante, Chambers and Lajoie. A Comparative Study of Public and Private Schools in the San Francisco Bay Area: A Descriptive Report (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- 84-A18. Chambers. Patterns of Comp of Public and Private School Teachers (Box 9, Folder 10)
- 84-A19. Glass. The Effectiveness of Four Education Interventions (Box 9, Folder 11)
- 84-A20. Murnane. The Rhetoric and Reality of Merit Pay (Box 9, Folder 12)
- 84-A21. Levin. Cost and Cost Effect of Computer Assisted Instruction (Box 9, Folder 13)
- 84-A22. Appelbaum. Technology and the Redesign of Work in the Insurance Industry (Box 9, Folder 14)
- 84-A23. Woo. The Shortage of Math and Science Teachers (Box 9, Folder 15)
- 84-A24. Rumberger. The Potential Impact of Technology on the Skill Requirements of Future Jobs (Box 9, Folder 16)
- 84-A25. Levin. Improving Productivity through Education and Technology (Box 10, Folder 1)
- 84-A26. Rumberger. Is there Really A Shortage of Math and Science Teachers? (Box 10, Folder 2)
- 84-A27. Strober and Arnold. Integrated Circuits/Segregated Labor: Women in Three Computer- Related Occupations (Box 10, Folder 3)
- 84-B1. McLauglin. Implementation Realities and Evaluation Design (Box 10, Folder 4)